<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>pacman on .blog</title><link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/tags/pacman/</link><description>Recent content in pacman on .blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>pt</language><copyright>Os conteúdos, da minha autoria, neste blog estão sob a licença [CC-BY-SA-4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.brunomiguel.net/tags/pacman/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Repositório com cara lavada</title><link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/repositorio-cara-lavada/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/repositorio-cara-lavada/</guid><description>O meu repositório de software para Arch Linux e distribuições compatíveis, Userrepository, levou umas alterações cosméticas para melhorar aquele aspeto cru normal de um open dir. Agora, quem acede a ele através do browser vai ver um template HTML todo catita com a listagem dos pacotes e uma link para o blog do repositório.
Esta alteração não tem qualquer impacto na forma como instalas os pacotes a partir de lá. Eles continuam à distância de um pacman -Syu como estavam anteriormente.</description></item><item><title>Status on userrepository changes</title><link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/status-on-userrepository-changes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/status-on-userrepository-changes/</guid><description>It took me a while to update you about the latest changes to my Arch and Arch-compatible Linux distributions repository. But first, let me apologize for the delay: work, personal life and, for about 3 weeks now, a horrible back pain (that just doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop, even with an handful of medication) have kept me from doing this in the time frame I expected.
First on the &amp;ldquo;agenda&amp;rdquo;, I experimented with increasing the zstd compression level for the packages like I said I would do in my last post about the repository.</description></item></channel></rss>