<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>endeavouros on .blog</title>
    <link>https://hugo-paper.vercel.app/tags/endeavouros/</link>
    <description>Recent content in endeavouros on .blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pt</language>
    <copyright>Os conteúdos, da minha autoria, neste blog estão sob a licença [CC-BY-SA-4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/)</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo-paper.vercel.app/tags/endeavouros/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ativar a indicação de bateria de headphones Bluetooth no Plasma Desktop</title>
      <link>https://hugo-paper.vercel.app/post/ativar-a-indicacao-de-bateria-de-headphones-bluetooth-no-plasma-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-paper.vercel.app/post/ativar-a-indicacao-de-bateria-de-headphones-bluetooth-no-plasma-desktop/</guid>
      <description>A última vez que atualizei este blog foi há pouco mais de 2 meses. Como não quero que ele fiquei muito tempo sem conteúdo novo, decidi escrever este post, uma dica útil para quem usa o Plasma Desktop e headphones Bluetooth, e quer ver a percentagem de bateria na applet.
Esta dica aplica-se a EndeavourOS, Arch Linux e outras distribuições baseadas em Arch. Noutras, o path do ficheiro pode ser diferente, por isso terás de ter isso em consideração se pretenderes replicá-a no teu sistema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A shitload of new packages on userrepository</title>
      <link>https://hugo-paper.vercel.app/post/a-shitload-of-new-packages-on-userrepository/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-paper.vercel.app/post/a-shitload-of-new-packages-on-userrepository/</guid>
      <description>Since the 24th of January, the date of the last blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a shitload of new packages to userrepository.eu. Some highlights are sonobus, media-downloader-git, baru, dotgit, timeshift, filmulator and tramp.
Expect more packages, as I&amp;rsquo;m adding new ones frequently. The focus on new packages will probably be scientific tools and maybe a kernel. With that, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have to increase the full build frequency from 8h to at least 9 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates on Userrepository and Jarvis</title>
      <link>https://hugo-paper.vercel.app/post/updates-on-userrepository-and-jarvis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-paper.vercel.app/post/updates-on-userrepository-and-jarvis/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having some problems when building picom-ibhagwan-git and picom-tryone-git. The first one would build OK, but not the second one.
After a bit of debugging, I found out that it was a problem related to the way makepkg and git handle the cache when building these forks. This would also happen when adding the picom-git package: it would build because it&amp;rsquo;s the first package in alphabetical order and Jarvis builds the packages that way, but not the other two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving boot time</title>
      <link>https://hugo-paper.vercel.app/post/improving-boot-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hugo-paper.vercel.app/post/improving-boot-time/</guid>
      <description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try and improve the boot time of my laptop, running EndeavourOS. There was no special reason for it other than &amp;ldquo;Why not?&amp;rdquo;.
The first thing I made was disabling or masking the following systemd services:
 systemd-resolved disabled tlp disabled NetworkManager-wait-online disabled lvm2-monitor masked org.cups.cupsd disabled packagekit masked bluetooth disabled (I rarely use the laptop&amp;rsquo;s bluetooth) blueman-mechanism disabled  With this, I was able to save a few milliseconds and decrease the enabled systemd units to 15, but the impact was negligible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
