<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on .blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on .blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pt</language>
    <copyright>[CC-BY-SA-4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/) - </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.brunomiguel.net/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ativar a indicação de bateria de headphones Bluetooth no Plasma Desktop</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/ativar-a-indicacao-de-bateria-de-headphones-bluetooth-no-plasma-desktop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/ativar-a-indicacao-de-bateria-de-headphones-bluetooth-no-plasma-desktop/</guid>
      <description>A última vez que atualizei este blog foi há pouco mais de 2 meses. Como não quero que ele fiquei muito tempo sem conteúdo novo, decidi escrever este post, uma dica útil para quem usa o Plasma Desktop e headphones Bluetooth, e quer ver a percentagem de bateria na applet.
Esta dica aplica-se a EndeavourOS, Arch Linux e outras distribuições baseadas em Arch. Noutras, o path do ficheiro pode ser diferente, por isso terás de ter isso em consideração se pretenderes replicá-a no teu sistema.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Userrepository using mirrors</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/userrepository-using-mirrors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/userrepository-using-mirrors/</guid>
      <description>For a few months, I considered using the mirror service from Fosshost in userrepository.eu. The service results from a partnership between Fosshost and Fastly, giving projects access to several PoP&amp;rsquo;s around the globe.
Finally, a few days ago, I enabled the service. I also created a package with the mirror&amp;rsquo;s list, userrepository-mirrors, available in my repository and AUR. The package has all the instructions for enabling the mirrors and what to do if you already have userrepository in your /etc/pacman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to disable a D-Bus service</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/how-to-disable-a-d-bus-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/how-to-disable-a-d-bus-service/</guid>
      <description>In some situations, you might want to disable a D-Bus service. One of those is, for example, when you use Dunst (a notification daemon) with a window manager. Still, you don&amp;rsquo;t want it to replace the notification daemon from your desktop environment.
To disable it, you just need to add .disabled to the end of the target file name. Example:
sudo mv /usr/share/dbus-1/services/org.knopwob.dunst.service /usr/share/dbus-1/services/org.knopwob.dunst.service.disabled In the above example, Dunst will no longer replace Plasma Desktop notification daemon when using that amazing desktop environment, and all will be good with the world again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status on userrepository changes</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/status-on-userrepository-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/status-on-userrepository-changes/</guid>
      <description>It took me a while to update you about the latest changes to my Arch and Arch-compatible Linux distributions repository. But first, let me apologize for the delay: work, personal life and, for about 3 weeks now, a horrible back pain (that just doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop, even with an handful of medication) have kept me from doing this in the time frame I expected.
First on the &amp;ldquo;agenda&amp;rdquo;, I experimented with increasing the zstd compression level for the packages like I said I would do in my last post about the repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My tools of trade in a Linux system</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/my-tools-of-trade-in-a-linux-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/my-tools-of-trade-in-a-linux-system/</guid>
      <description>With no special order:
Desktop environments and/or window managers plasma (to me, the best desktop environment for any free software operating system) i3wm (paired with picom [https://github.com/ibhagwan/picom] for transparency, blur and rounded corners) Terminal emulators konsole (I&amp;rsquo;ve grown very fond if this terminal emulator since I switched to the plasma desktop, and it has blur for the blings ;)) urxvt-unicode (with tabbedex, so I can have tabs with it) Text editors micro (my favorite and because it supports gui keybinds, although it&amp;rsquo;s a cli text editor) nano (simple and super useful, available by default in a lot of linux distributions) vim (I have a custom mode for writing markdown text) gedit (for when I need a text editor with a gui) Note taking qownnotes Browsers firefox (my favorite for around a decade and an half.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving boot time</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/improving-boot-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/improving-boot-time/</guid>
      <description>Today, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try and improve the boot time of my laptop, running EndeavourOS. There was no special reason for it other than &amp;ldquo;Why not?&amp;rdquo;.
The first thing I made was disabling or masking the following systemd services:
systemd-resolved disabled tlp disabled NetworkManager-wait-online disabled lvm2-monitor masked org.cups.cupsd disabled packagekit masked bluetooth disabled (I rarely use the laptop&amp;rsquo;s bluetooth) blueman-mechanism disabled With this, I was able to save a few milliseconds and decrease the enabled systemd units to 15, but the impact was negligible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MintBox 3 disponível</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/mintbox-3-disponivel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/mintbox-3-disponivel/</guid>
      <description>O MintBox3, o computador desenvolvido pela Compulab em parceria com o projeto Linux Mint, chegou. O equipamento está disponível em duas edições, Basic e Pro, e vem com a versão mais recente da distribuição, Linux Mint 19.3 Tricia, pré-instalada.
Esta é a quinta interação do MintBox. A estética mantém-se semelhante às versões anteriores e apresenta uma boa capacidade de processamento, para além de algumas características interessantes, como uma quantidade bastante grande de portas USB (9 na versão Basic e 10 na versão Pro).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Userrepository now on Arch Wiki</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/userrepository-now-on-arch-wiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/userrepository-now-on-arch-wiki/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to the suggestion made by &amp;lsquo;guser&amp;rsquo;, I&amp;rsquo;ve added my repository to the Arch Wiki, in the non-signed section. I hope Arch Linux users may find it useful.
Since I&amp;rsquo;m writing a post about userrepository, I&amp;rsquo;ll take the chance to list all packages currently available at the time of writing:
acestream-engine acestream-launcher adwaita-qt adwm aerc android-messages-desktop archuseriso athenaeum-git atom-editor-bin axmud bindfs bindmap-git bitwarden-bin boostnote-bin bootiso boston-icon-theme-git brackets brave-dev-bin brightnessctl-git broot cava cawbird-git cht.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates on my Arch/Manjaro repository</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/updates-on-my-arch-manjaro-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/updates-on-my-arch-manjaro-repository/</guid>
      <description>Ever since Carlos Silva left a comment on my last post about this repository, I was left wondering if it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be better to migrate my current VM to Scaleway. The price/specs seemed better and for the marginal difference of €1 I would get a dual-core virtual machine with 2GB of RAM and 50Gb of disk space.
After a couple of weeks of reflection, I bought a “Start1-S” VPS for €3,99/month and I&amp;rsquo;ve been (successfully) testing aurto to manage the repository updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve built a Manjaro repository</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/ive-built-a-manjaro-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/ive-built-a-manjaro-repository/</guid>
      <description>Due to my own dumbness (I mistakenly deleted my Ubuntu partition), I installed Manjaro, using the Manjaro Architect release, on my laptop. I&amp;rsquo;d been thinking about doing it for a while and finally made it because I was too stupid to read the instructions from cfdisk. The shit you create yourself because you&amp;rsquo;re in a hurry…
Anyway, after installing Manjaro, I started reading a bit about this distro packaging and how I could leverage AUR and binary packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agora já sou geek</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/agora-ja-sou-geek/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/agora-ja-sou-geek/</guid>
      <description>Hoje chegaram os autocolantes que encomendei no Sticker Mule em dezembro, numa promoção em que o pack ficava a €1 e pouco. Com isto, já posso dizer que sou geek e o meu portátil ficou &amp;ldquo;lit af&amp;rdquo;.
Só tenho pena que o pack não incluísse um autocolante do projeto GNU. Teria sido ouro sobre azul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying Debian Stable for everyday desktop usage</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/trying-debian-stable-for-everyday-desktop-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/trying-debian-stable-for-everyday-desktop-usage/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago I installed Debian Stable. I&amp;rsquo;d been using Sparky Linux, which is based on Debian Testing, and was happy with it. The tools it integrates make the life of a desktop user easier when managing the system, I had no issues with it and had a bunch of software available in the repositories.
Well, since Sparky is based on Debian, the &amp;ldquo;bunch of software available in the repositories&amp;rdquo; part was a given from the start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to install an operating system to a USB drive</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/how-to-install-an-operating-system-to-a-usb-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/how-to-install-an-operating-system-to-a-usb-drive/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, maybe for maintenance or data rescue reasons, you may want to have a USB thumbdrive with a GNU/Linux distribution installed. I&amp;rsquo;m not referring to writing a live ISO to a USB drive; I really mean having the distribution installed like it would be on an hard drive. An easy way to achieve this is using the virtualization software Qemu. Example:
sudo qemu-system-x86_64 -boot d -cdrom void-live-x86_64-20171007.iso -hda /dev/sdb -m 800 In this example, the -hda /dev/sdb part tells Qemu that the device /dev/sdb (the USB drive) must be used as an hard drive.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
