<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>userrepository-eu on .blog</title>
    <link>/tags/userrepository-eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in userrepository-eu on .blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pt</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/userrepository-eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Userrepository using mirrors</title>
      <link>/post/userrepository-using-mirrors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/userrepository-using-mirrors/</guid>
      <description>For a few months, I considered using the mirror service from Fosshost in userrepository.eu. The service results from a partnership between Fosshost and Fastly, giving projects access to several PoP&amp;rsquo;s around the globe.
Finally, a few days ago, I enabled the service. I also created a package with the mirror&amp;rsquo;s list, userrepository-mirrors, available in my repository and AUR. The package has all the instructions for enabling the mirrors and what to do if you already have userrepository in your /etc/pacman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A shitload of new packages on userrepository</title>
      <link>/post/a-shitload-of-new-packages-on-userrepository/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-shitload-of-new-packages-on-userrepository/</guid>
      <description>Since the 24th of January, the date of the last blog post, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a shitload of new packages to userrepository.eu. Some highlights are sonobus, media-downloader-git, baru, dotgit, timeshift, filmulator and tramp.
Expect more packages, as I&amp;rsquo;m adding new ones frequently. The focus on new packages will probably be scientific tools and maybe a kernel. With that, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have to increase the full build frequency from 8h to at least 9 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some changes to userrepository</title>
      <link>/post/some-changes-to-userrepository/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/some-changes-to-userrepository/</guid>
      <description>Hello, folks. It has been a while since I last wrote about my AUR-based Arch Linux repository. To be precise, four months and twelve days.
A lot has happened since then. One of the main changes was the removal of several packages no longer present in AUR or really outdated. Some examples are peafox, marp and gimp-dbp.
Another important change was the addition of several new packages, as usual. If I find it may be useful for someone, I add it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some statistics for Userrepository</title>
      <link>/post/some-statistics-for-userrepository/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/some-statistics-for-userrepository/</guid>
      <description>You might have noticed that Userrepository uses Cloudflare. I chose it for two main reasons: their ability to help mitigate (D)DoS attacks and to help hiding the IP address for the VM from script kiddies.
It&amp;rsquo;s not that I think Userrepository will ever be a target for a (D)DoS attack, but better safe than sorry. Also, I have more than enough automated failed SSH authentication attempts without revealing the IP: 441 blocked _IP_s and counting for one fail2ban ssh rule and 2 for another fail2ban ssh rule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status on userrepository changes</title>
      <link>/post/status-on-userrepository-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/status-on-userrepository-changes/</guid>
      <description>It took me a while to update you about the latest changes to my Arch and Arch-compatible Linux distributions repository. But first, let me apologize for the delay: work, personal life and, for about 3 weeks now, a horrible back pain (that just doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop, even with an handful of medication) have kept me from doing this in the time frame I expected.
First on the &amp;ldquo;agenda&amp;rdquo;, I experimented with increasing the zstd compression level for the packages like I said I would do in my last post about the repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates on userrepository</title>
      <link>/post/updates-on-userrepository/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/updates-on-userrepository/</guid>
      <description>Since the last post about my Arch (and Arch-compatible distributions) binary repository, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a few more packages. Some examples are the Mullvad VPN desktop client and nimdow, a window manager written in the Nim programming language. Or Emptty, an amazing display manager that I encourage you to try.
Despite adding more packages, the compilation and compression time only had a small increase and I&amp;rsquo;m still below the 5 hour mark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some notes about userrepository performance with the new provider</title>
      <link>/post/some-notes-about-userrepository-performance-with-the-new-provider/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/some-notes-about-userrepository-performance-with-the-new-provider/</guid>
      <description>In the previous post, I wrote about how I changed the virtual machine provider from Scaleway to Hetzner. In the days following the transition, I timed how much it took to build all the packages and sync them to the webserver, so I could compare the new provider with the previous one.
The specs are very similar: 4 vCPUs and 8GB of RAM. There is one difference, however: with Scaleway, the vCPUs were some Intel low-end ones (although they&amp;rsquo;ve upgraded to AMD EPYC very recently) and with Hetzer they are AMD EPYC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Userrepository.eu is back (in beta)</title>
      <link>/post/userrepository-eu-is-back-in-beta/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/userrepository-eu-is-back-in-beta/</guid>
      <description>After a small forced hiatus, userrepository.eu is back. The Covid-19 pandemic made a hit in my income and the wife&amp;rsquo;s income, so I had to temporarily suspend non-priority expenses. During this period, I had time to consider a few things about the future of the project and decided to change the provider from Scaleway to Hetzner, mostly because the Arch image they&amp;rsquo;re using is essentially abandonware.
If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this, you&amp;rsquo;ll probably know that Arch Linux changed the default package compression to ZSTD.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging build times</title>
      <link>/post/debugging-build-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/debugging-build-times/</guid>
      <description>Lately, the repository has been taking +10 hours to compile all the packages. I think that&amp;rsquo;s a lot for a little more than 250 packages, most of them small utilities and/or _-bin_ files from AUR, built in a DEV1-L (4 cores, 8 Gb RAM) virtual machine from Scaleway.
After investigating the matter, I found out that 12 of the packages took four hours and sixteen minutes to build.
   Pkg Hours Minutes     .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Suporte para o Cartão de Cidadão no userrepository.eu</title>
      <link>/post/suporte-para-o-cartao-de-cidadao-no-userrepository-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/suporte-para-o-cartao-de-cidadao-no-userrepository-eu/</guid>
      <description>Ainda hoje, no máximo amanhã, devo disponibilizar a aplicação para autenticação nas plataformas do Estado com o Cartão de Cidadão. Assim que estiver disponível, basta usares o comando sudo pacman -Syyuv autenticacao-gov-pt para ser feita a instalação. Não te esqueças de adicionar o repositório primeiro, caso ainda não o tenhas feito. Fica atent@.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates to Jarvis, my Arch buildbot</title>
      <link>/post/updates-to-jarvis-my-arch-buildbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/updates-to-jarvis-my-arch-buildbot/</guid>
      <description>My Arch buildbot, Jarvis, received an update today in the options logic. Now, it can receive an argument in the add (-a) and delete (-d) options, so the user can specify the package to add or delete.
The option to add a package, for now, only works for AUR. If you want to add a package that&amp;rsquo;s not in AUR, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to manually add the submodule. In the future, Jarvis will allow you to use a git repository with a PKGBUILD file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First own package on userrepository.eu</title>
      <link>/post/first-own-package-on-userrepository-eu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/first-own-package-on-userrepository-eu/</guid>
      <description>Until now, userrepository.eu only used software from AUR. Today, to get me distracted from the flu and a respiratory infection I got a few days ago, I&amp;rsquo;ve finally created my first package for Arch Linux on my repository. It&amp;rsquo;s for a GTK web browser named Eoli and it builds from the master git branch.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the PKGBUILD at the time of writing:
# Maintainer: Bruno Miguel  ​ pkgname=eolie-git _gitname=eolie pkgver=da1899ff pkgrel=1 pkgdesc=&amp;ldquo;Simple GTK web browser for GNOME&amp;rdquo; arch=(&amp;lsquo;x86_64&amp;rsquo;) url=&amp;ldquo;https://wiki.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Userrepository.eu now available on Github</title>
      <link>/post/userrepository-eu-now-available-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/userrepository-eu-now-available-on-github/</guid>
      <description>My Arch/Manjaro (and any other Arch-based distro) repository continues to receive more packages from AUR. But this post is not about that. I&amp;rsquo;m writing this because I published the scripts I&amp;rsquo;m using to build the packages for userrepository.eu. You can get them at Github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
