<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>aur on .blog</title>
    <link>/tags/aur/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aur on .blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pt</language>
    <copyright>[CC-BY-SA-4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/) - </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/aur/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Userrepository using mirrors</title>
      <link>/post/userrepository-using-mirrors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/userrepository-using-mirrors/</guid>
      <description>For a few months, I considered using the mirror service from Fosshost in userrepository.eu. The service results from a partnership between Fosshost and Fastly, giving projects access to several PoP&amp;rsquo;s around the globe.
Finally, a few days ago, I enabled the service. I also created a package with the mirror&amp;rsquo;s list, userrepository-mirrors, available in my repository and AUR. The package has all the instructions for enabling the mirrors and what to do if you already have userrepository in your /etc/pacman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dark theme for AUR</title>
      <link>/post/a-dark-theme-for-aur/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-dark-theme-for-aur/</guid>
      <description>I love AUR. Being able to use a simple PKGBUILD to install a software not available in the official Arch repositories is a blessing. Sadly, its user experience and looks need improvements to bring it to the 21st century.
One of the things that bug me the most is the microscopic font size. I almost need a telescope to read the text.
To fix it, and make it smoother on the eyes, I created a dark theme for AUR.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates on Userrepository and Jarvis</title>
      <link>/post/updates-on-userrepository-and-jarvis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/updates-on-userrepository-and-jarvis/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having some problems when building picom-ibhagwan-git and picom-tryone-git. The first one would build OK, but not the second one.
After a bit of debugging, I found out that it was a problem related to the way makepkg and git handle the cache when building these forks. This would also happen when adding the picom-git package: it would build because it&amp;rsquo;s the first package in alphabetical order and Jarvis builds the packages that way, but not the other two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates on my Arch/Manjaro repository</title>
      <link>/post/updates-on-my-arch-manjaro-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/updates-on-my-arch-manjaro-repository/</guid>
      <description>Ever since Carlos Silva left a comment on my last post about this repository, I was left wondering if it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be better to migrate my current VM to Scaleway. The price/specs seemed better and for the marginal difference of €1 I would get a dual-core virtual machine with 2GB of RAM and 50Gb of disk space.
After a couple of weeks of reflection, I bought a “Start1-S” VPS for €3,99/month and I&amp;rsquo;ve been (successfully) testing aurto to manage the repository updates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve built a Manjaro repository</title>
      <link>/post/ive-built-a-manjaro-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ive-built-a-manjaro-repository/</guid>
      <description>Due to my own dumbness (I mistakenly deleted my Ubuntu partition), I installed Manjaro, using the Manjaro Architect release, on my laptop. I&amp;rsquo;d been thinking about doing it for a while and finally made it because I was too stupid to read the instructions from cfdisk. The shit you create yourself because you&amp;rsquo;re in a hurry…
Anyway, after installing Manjaro, I started reading a bit about this distro packaging and how I could leverage AUR and binary packages.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
