<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Privacy on .blog</title>
    <link>/tags/privacy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Privacy on .blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pt</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/privacy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chrome extensions hellscape</title>
      <link>/post/chrome-extensions-hellscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/chrome-extensions-hellscape/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been experiencing reduced performance with Firefox for a few releases now. This decrease in performance happens even with a clean profile. So, I began testing other browsers. Two of them are Chromium and Brave. They are nice and whatnot, but they have two issues in common: they threaten browser engine diversity (remember the Internet Explorer dominance days and how that negatively impacted the web?) and the Chrome Store hellscape. There are a lot - and I mean a lot - of proprietary extensions on the Chrome Store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google Chrome is a privacy hell</title>
      <link>/post/google-chrome-is-a-privacy-hell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/google-chrome-is-a-privacy-hell/</guid>
      <description>Google Chrome is such a privacy hell that it has become it&amp;rsquo;s own hell in the japanese folklore. You&amp;rsquo;re better off with Firefox and you get better performance. But if you really want Chrome, Ungoogled Chromium is based on the previous (technically, it&amp;rsquo;s based on Chromium) with some bits removed for added privacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Criptex, an encripted email service with focus on privacy</title>
      <link>/post/criptex-an-encripted-email-service-with-focus-on-privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/criptex-an-encripted-email-service-with-focus-on-privacy/</guid>
      <description>Criptex is a new email client with a strong focus on the user&amp;rsquo;s privacy and data security, released by an independent company with the same name. The app stores all the emails on the device(s) it&amp;rsquo;s used, encrypted with the Signal Protocol, instead of storing them in their servers. This gives user&amp;rsquo;s total control over their data.
This software is open source and available for Android, iOS and macOS. Linux and Windows releases will be available soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
