<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>science on .blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/tags/science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in science on .blog</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pt</language>
    <copyright>[CC-BY-SA-4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/) - </copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.brunomiguel.net/tags/science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Folding@home</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/foldinghome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/foldinghome/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago, I decided to use my VPS spare CPU cycles to help out the Folding@home (F@h) project.
If you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of F@H, here is a description from their website:
 Folding@home (FAH or F@h) is a distributed computing project for disease research that simulates protein folding, computational drug design, and other types of molecular dynamics. As of today, the project is using the idle resources of personal computers owned by volunteers from all over the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Astronomers found a remnant from the Big Bang</title>
      <link>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/astronomers-found-a-remnant-of-the-big-bang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.brunomiguel.net/post/astronomers-found-a-remnant-of-the-big-bang/</guid>
      <description>Simulation of galaxies and gas in the universe. Within the gas in the (blue) filaments connecting the (orange) galaxies lurk rare pockets of pristine gas – vestiges of the Big Bang that have somehow been orphaned from the explosive, polluting deaths of stars, seen here as circular shock waves around some orange points. CREDIT: TNG COLLABORATION
[Jim Parsons inserted by me]
This is huge! A group of astronomers, led by Fred Robert and Michael Murphy of the Swinburne University of Technology in Australia, found a cloud of gas left over from the Big Bang, using the telescope located at W.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
